<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<displaySet>
   <glossary>
      <characters>
         <alphabet>All</alphabet>
         <alphabet>A</alphabet>
         <alphabet>B</alphabet>
         <alphabet>C</alphabet>
         <alphabet>D</alphabet>
         <alphabet>E</alphabet>
         <alphabet>F</alphabet>
         <alphabet>G</alphabet>
         <alphabet>H</alphabet>
         <alphabet>I</alphabet>
         <alphabet>J</alphabet>
         <alphabet>K</alphabet>
         <alphabet>L</alphabet>
         <alphabet>M</alphabet>
         <alphabet>N</alphabet>
         <alphabet>O</alphabet>
         <alphabet>P</alphabet>
         <alphabet>Q</alphabet>
         <alphabet>R</alphabet>
         <alphabet>S</alphabet>
         <alphabet>T</alphabet>
         <alphabet>U</alphabet>
         <alphabet>V</alphabet>
         <alphabet>W</alphabet>
         <alphabet>X</alphabet>
         <alphabet>Y</alphabet>
         <alphabet>Z</alphabet>
      </characters>
      <chapter chapNumber="1">
		<medicine medName="Acidosis" letter="a" audioFile="">Refers to the blood pH of &lt; 7.35 by the overproduction of acid that builds up in the blood and/or excessive loss of bicarbonate from the blood (metabolic acidosis). Acidosis can also be due to a buildup of carbon dioxide in the blood secondary to poor lung function or depressed breathing (respiratory acidosis).</medicine>
        <medicine medName="Acute Renal Failure" letter="a" audioFile="">Also called acute kidney failure or acute kidney injury, occurs when the kidneys become unable to filter waste products from the blood.</medicine>
		<medicine medName="Adenovirus" letter="a" audioFile="">Description here.</medicine>
		<medicine medName="Adrenal Gland" letter="a" audioFile="">Two endocrine glands found above each kidney that produce a variety of hormones including glucocorticoids (primarily cortisol), mineralocorticoids (primarily aldosterone), and androgens. Cells in the adrenal medulla produce epinephrine and smaller amounts of norepinephrine.</medicine>
		<medicine medName="Aerobic Metabolism" letter="a" audioFile="">Refers to the chemical process used to convert fat, carbohydrate, and protein into energy, but only in the presence of oxygen. Under aerobic conditions, 1 molecule of glucose will produce 38 molecules of adenosine triphosphate (ATP).</medicine>
		<medicine medName="Afterload" letter="a" audioFile="">Measure of the pressure against which the heart pumps.</medicine>
		<medicine medName="Air Bronchogram" letter="a" audioFile="">Dark, tubular outline of bronchi that are made visible by surrounding, often poorly expanded, lung tissue. </medicine>
		<medicine medName="Alveoli" letter="a" audioFile="">Tiny cup-shaped air sacs located in the lung parenchyma. Oxygen and carbon dioxide are exchanged at the alveoli-capillary interface. The human lung contains millions of alveoli. </medicine>
		<medicine medName="Amniocentesis" letter="a" audioFile="">Description here. </medicine>
		<medicine medName="Anaerobic Metabolism" letter="a" audioFile="">Lack of oxygen results in incomplete metabolism of glucose into energy, or adenosine triphosphate (ATP). Under anaerobic conditions, 1 molecule of glucose will produce 2 molecules of ATP and 2 molecules of lactic acid.</medicine>
		<medicine medName="Arrhythmia" letter="a" audioFile="">An abnormality in the generation or conduction of electrical impulses in the heart. Consequences can include tachycardia, bradycardia, or an irregular heart rhythm. Also known as dysrhythmia.</medicine>
		<medicine medName="Asphyxia" letter="a" audioFile="">An extreme condition of impaired gas exchange that results in hypoxemia (low blood oxygen levels) and hypercarbia (elevated carbon dioxide levels). The state of asphyxia is caused by interruption of breathing and inadequate oxygen supply to the tissues. Asphyxia can lead to unconsciousness and, if untreated in a timely manner, death.</medicine>
		<medicine medName="Asphyxial" letter="a" audioFile="">Refers to the extreme condition secondary to interference with respiration that leads to lack of oxygen and excessive amounts of carbon dioxide in the blood.</medicine>
		<medicine medName="Atelectasis" letter="a" audioFile=""><![CDATA[Collapse or closure of a portion of the lung that leads to reduced or absent <br>gas exchange.]]></medicine>
		<medicine medName="Atresia" letter="a" audioFile=""><![CDATA[The congenital absence, or the pathological closure, of an opening, <br>passage, or cavity.]]></medicine>
		<medicine medName="Bacteria" letter="b" audioFile="">Microscopic, single-celled organisms that do not have a nucleus. Some bacteria are pathologic, meaning they can cause disease; other forms of bacteria have a useful, non-harmful purpose. Bacterial shapes include spheres, rods, and spirals.</medicine>
		<medicine medName="Ballard Exam" letter="b" audioFile="">A scorable test to assess newborn gestational age using physical and neuromuscular maturity parameters. The exam should be performed by 24 hours of age.</medicine>
		<medicine medName="Basophil" letter="b" audioFile="">Description here.</medicine>
		<medicine medName="Bile" letter="b" audioFile="media/bile">A greenish or yellow fluid that is made by the liver, stored in the gallbladder, and passes through the common bile duct into the duodenum, where it helps digest fat. Bile also helps neutralize excess stomach acid. </medicine>
		<medicine medName="Bilious Emesis" letter="b" audioFile="">Vomit that has a green or yellow color secondary to presence of bile. One of the cardinal signs of bowel obstruction is bilious emesis.</medicine>
		<medicine medName="Birth Asphyxia" letter="b" audioFile="">Occurs when there is a known perinatal event that is capable of impairing perfusion and oxygen delivery to the fetus or newborn, resulting in hypoxia, acidemia, and metabolic acidosis.</medicine>
		<medicine medName="Blood Urea Nitrogen (BUN)" letter="b" audioFile="">A chemical waste produced when protein is broken down. BUN is removed from the body in the urine. In neonates, an elevated BUN may indicate impaired kidney function, dehydration, or heart failure.</medicine>
		<medicine medName="Body Mass Index (BMI)" letter="b" audioFile="">A weight-to-height ratio that is used to identify weight categories.</medicine>
		<medicine medName="Brachial Plexus Injury" letter="b" audioFile="">Excessive stretching or tearing of the brachial plexus (the network of nerves that send signals from your spinal cord to your shoulder, arm and hand) during delivery. Symptoms of injury include a limp or paralyzed arm, lack of muscle control in the arm, hand, or wrist, and lack of feeling in the arm or hand. Infants injured during birth often improve or recover by 3 to 4 months of age. </medicine>
		<medicine medName="Bronchi" letter="b" audioFile="">Cartilage-containing tubular structures that conduct air from the upper airways to the lower lung parenchyma. Bronchioles are the respiratory tubules distal to the bronchi and they do not contain cartilage. </medicine>
		<medicine medName="Cardiac Output" letter="c" audioFile="">The amount of blood pumped by the heart over time. Cardiac output is determined by heart rate, heart contractility, preload, and afterload.  </medicine>
		<medicine medName="Catecholamines" letter="c" audioFile=""><![CDATA[Medications used in the treatment of shock to induce vasoconstriction to help increase mean arterial pressure or to enhance inotropic effect to increase cardiac contractility. Example medications include epinephrine, norepinephrine, <br>and dopamine.]]></medicine>
		<medicine medName="Cerebral Palsy" letter="c" audioFile="">The leading cause of childhood disability, affecting both child development and function. Signs of cerebral palsy include a history of gross motor developmental delay in the first year of life and abnormal muscle tone.</medicine>
		<medicine medName="Chorionic Villus Sampling" letter="c" audioFile="">Description here.</medicine>
		<medicine medName="Coagulation" letter="c" audioFile="">The complex process of making a blood clot. Cells (platelets) and coagulation factors (proteins) interact to help form the blood clot.</medicine>
		<medicine medName="Cord Prolapse" letter="c" audioFile=""><![CDATA[A complication that occurs prior to or during the delivery of the baby. In a prolapse, the umbilical cord drops (prolapses) through the open cervix into the vagina ahead of the baby. The cord can then become trapped against the baby’s body <br>during delivery.]]></medicine>
		<medicine medName="Coronavirus" letter="c" audioFile="">Description here.</medicine>
		<medicine medName="Creatinine" letter="c" audioFile="">Creatinine is a waste product produced by muscles from the breakdown of creatine. The kidneys filter almost all of the creatinine from the blood, where it is then removed from the body in the urine. Elevated levels of creatinine in the blood may reflect kidney damage.</medicine>
		<medicine medName="Cyanosis" letter="c" audioFile="">Used to describe bluish or purplish discoloration of the skin or mucous membranes secondary to presence of poorly oxygenated hemoglobin. The root of the word, “cyan,” refers to a blue-green color.</medicine>
		<medicine medName="Cytomegalovirus (CMV)" letter="c" audioFile="">A common virus related to the herpes virus.</medicine>
		<medicine medName="Dextrocardia" letter="d" audioFile=""><![CDATA[A rare congenital condition where the apex and four chambers of the heart point to the right side of the chest instead of the normal orientation in the left side of <br>the chest.]]></medicine>
		<medicine medName="Diaphoresis" letter="d" audioFile="">Sweating, especially to an unusual degree as a symptom of disease or a side effect of a drug.</medicine>
		<medicine medName="Disseminated Intravascular Coagulation (DIC)" letter="d" audioFile=""><![CDATA[A condition where blood coagulation is abnormally activated as a complication of severe illness. This abnormal clotting then causes damage to the microvasculature (e.g., the capillaries, arterioles, and venules), and in severe cases can cause <br>organ dysfunction.]]></medicine>
		<medicine medName="Ductus Arteriosus" letter="d" audioFile="">In utero, the ductus arteriosus is a blood vessel that connects the pulmonary artery to the aorta. After birth, the ductus arteriosus should constrict and close.</medicine>
		<medicine medName="Echocardiogram" letter="e" audioFile="">A test that uses high frequency sound waves, or ultrasound, to evaluate the heart chambers, valves, septal walls, and vessels that are attached to the heart, i.e., the great vessels (aorta and pulmonary artery) and veins (superior vena cava, inferior vena cava, and pulmonary veins).</medicine>
		<medicine medName="Electrocardiogram (ECG)" letter="e" audioFile="">Measures electrical activity of the heart to detect cardiac problems.</medicine>
		<medicine medName="Enterovirus" letter="e" audioFile="">Description here.</medicine>
		<medicine medName="Eosinophil" letter="e" audioFile="">Description here.</medicine>
		<medicine medName="Epilepsy" letter="e" audioFile="">A central nervous system disorder in which brain activity becomes abnormal and causes recurrent seizures, loss of awareness, or loss of consciousness. A seizure is defined as an abnormal disorderly discharging of the brain’s nerve cells. In general, at least two unprovoked seizures are required for an epilepsy diagnosis. </medicine>
		<medicine medName="Fetal Heart Tracing: Category I" letter="f" audioFile="">Fetal heart tracing that predicts a normal fetal acid-base status. Specific characteristics include a baseline heart rate between 110 and 160 beats per minute; moderate baseline fetal heart rate variability (amplitude range between 6 to 25 beats per minute); and no late or variable decelerations. Early decelerations may be present or absent, and acceleration may be present or absent (abrupt increase in fetal heart rate above the most recent baseline). </medicine>
		<medicine medName="Fetal Heart Tracing: Category II" letter="f" audioFile="">Fetal heart tracing that is indeterminate and therefore requires ongoing surveillance and re-evaluation. Specific characteristics include bradycardia without absent variability (heart rate less than 110 beats per minute); tachycardia; minimal or marked fetal heart rate variability (minimal: amplitude range is detectable but less than 5 beats per minute; marked: amplitude range is greater than 25 beats per minute); absent variability without recurrent decelerations; absence of accelerations after induced fetal stimulation; recurrent variable decelerations with minimal or moderate baseline fetal heart rate variability (as above); prolonged decelerations or recurrent late decelerations with moderate baseline fetal heart rate variability (amplitude range is 6 to 25 beats per minute); variable decelerations with other characteristics such as slow return to baseline. </medicine>
		<medicine medName="Fetal Heart Tracing: Category III" letter="f" audioFile=""><![CDATA[Fetal heart tracing that predicts an abnormal fetal acid-base status and that requires intervention. Specific characteristics include absent variability with recurrent late decelerations, or recurrent variable decelerations, or bradycardia. <br>Sinusoidal pattern.]]></medicine>
		<medicine medName="Fetal-to-Maternal Hemorrhage (FMH)" letter="f" audioFile="">Loss of fetal blood into the maternal circulation before or during delivery. Most pregnancies include a small amount of fetal blood contamination into the maternal circulation. However, a large FMH will compromise the fetus and may result in fetal death, stillbirth, or delivery of a severely anemic infant. The incidence of severe FMH is 1 in 1,000 deliveries.</medicine>
		<medicine medName="Fungi" letter="f" audioFile="">Plural for the word fungus. Fungi are organisms or pathogens that include yeast and mold. Fungal infections may be life threatening for immunocompromised neonates.</medicine>
		<medicine medName="Gastroschisis" letter="g" audioFile="">An abdominal wall defect that allows herniation of intestine and, in more complex cases, other organs outside of the abdominal cavity. There is no covering membrane, which allows the intestine to be exposed to the amniotic fluid. Gastroschisis occurs just to the right of the umbilical cord, although in rare cases, the defect may originate from the left side of the umbilicus. There is no known genetic association at this time. Other anomalies are not common; however, in a small percentage of patients, there may be central nervous system, cardiovascular, limb, or kidney anomalies. The incidence of gastroschisis is 1 in 2,000 births. </medicine>
		<medicine medName="Glottis" letter="g" audioFile=""><![CDATA[The middle part of the larynx where the vocal cords are located. The larynx has three parts: the supraglottis (which includes the epiglottis), the glottis, and <br>the subglottis.]]></medicine>
		<medicine medName="Glycogen" letter="g" audioFile="">A substance deposited in bodily tissues as a store of glucose. Glycogen is stored primarily in the liver and skeletal muscle, although small amounts may also be found in the heart and lungs. </medicine>
		<medicine medName="Gram-positive  organism" letter="g" audioFile="">Gram staining refers to a bacterial staining procedure developed by a Danish bacteriologist, Hans Christian Gram in 1883. Gram staining is the first step in identifying an organism. The procedure allows differentiation of bacteria into one of two categories – positive or negative. The determination is based on color change. Organisms that stain a blue/purple color (because they retain the stain applied to them) are Gram-positive bacteria. Organisms that stain a pink/reddish color(because they lose their color when the destaining step is performed) are Gram-negative bacteria.. </medicine>
		<medicine medName="Gram-negative  organism" letter="g" audioFile="">Gram staining refers to a bacterial staining procedure developed by a Danish bacteriologist, Hans Christian Gram in 1883. Gram staining is the first step in identifying an organism. The procedure allows differentiation of bacteria into one of two categories – positive or negative. The determination is based on color change. Organisms that stain a blue/purple color (because they retain the stain applied to them) are Gram-positive bacteria. Organisms that stain a pink/reddish color(because they lose their color when the destaining step is performed) are Gram-negative bacteria. </medicine>
		<medicine medName="Hepatitis" letter="h" audioFile=""><![CDATA[An inflammation of the liver that is usually caused by a viral infection. Other causes of hepatitis include toxins (alcohol and certain medications) and <br>autoimmune disease.]]></medicine>
		<medicine medName="Herpes Simplex Virus (HSV)" letter="h" audioFile="">A virus that is categorized as one of two types: HSV-1 (oral herpes) or HSV-2 (genital herpes). HSV-1 usually causes sores around the mouth and lips, but it can also cause genital herpes. HSV-2 most commonly infects the genitals or rectum. HSV-2 lesions may be found in other areas, but most commonly they are found below the waist.</medicine>
		<medicine medName="Human Immunodeficiency Virus (HIV)" letter="h" audioFile="">A virus that is spread through certain body fluids and that attacks the immune system. Transmission from an infected mother to her child can be through pregnancy, birth, or breastfeeding. Even with treatment, HIV is never completely eradicated; however, with effective antiretroviral therapy, people can live long and healthy lives. Poorly controlled HIV infection can lead to acquired immunodeficiency syndrome (AIDS).</medicine>
		<medicine medName="Hyperbilirubinemia" letter="h" audioFile="media/hyperbilirubinemia">The presence of excess bilirubin in the blood. Bilirubin is a yellow substance that is made from hemoglobin during normal breakdown of aging red blood cells.</medicine>
		<medicine medName="Hyperviscosity" letter="h" audioFile="media/hyperviscosity">An abnormal increase in the viscosity or thickness of blood.</medicine>
		<medicine medName="Hypocalcemia" letter="h" audioFile="media/hypocalcemia">A deficiency of calcium in the blood. Calcium is the most abundant mineral in the body and is needed for many bodily functions including muscle and blood vessel contraction, blood clotting, regulation of heartbeat, building strong bones and teeth, nerve impulse and transmission, and as a co-factor for many enzymes.</medicine>
		<medicine medName="Hypoglycemia" letter="h" audioFile="">A condition caused by a low level of sugar (glucose) in the blood.</medicine>
		<medicine medName="Hypothalamus" letter="h" audioFile="">Region at the base of the brain near the pituitary gland that is involved in many functions, including regulation of body temperature. </medicine>
		<medicine medName="Hypoxemia" letter="h" audioFile="media/hypoxemia">Low level of oxygen in the blood.</medicine>
		<medicine medName="Hypoxia" letter="h" audioFile="">Reduced oxygen supply to the tissues below physiological levels required for normal cell functioning.</medicine>
		<medicine medName="Hypoxic Ischemic Encephalopathy (HIE)" letter="h" audioFile="media/hypoxic_ischemic_encephalopathy">Occurs when an acute perinatal event causes the brain to be deprived of an adequate supply of oxygen.  </medicine>
		<medicine medName="Ileus" letter="i" audioFile="media/ileus">A temporary arrest of intestinal peristalsis (forward propulsion of intestinal contents), somewhere in the intestinal tract. </medicine>
		<medicine medName="Inborn Errors Of Metabolism" letter="i" audioFile="">Inborn errors of metabolism are genetic disorders that are usually caused by a block in a metabolic pathway secondary to a defect in an enzyme or transport protein. Primary effects include either toxic accumulation of substrates that cannot be metabolized or broken down, or inability to make an essential product because of a missing intermediary.</medicine>	
		<medicine medName="Ischemia/Ischemic" letter="i" audioFile="">Restriction in blood supply and therefore in oxygen delivery to the tissues. Secondary effects include poor nutrient delivery to the tissues and inadequate removal of metabolic wastes. Ischemia results in tissue damage and may progress to tissue necrosis. </medicine>
		<medicine medName="Lactic Acid" letter="l" audioFile="">Produced in the red blood cells and muscle cells when carbohydrates are broken down to use for energy, and when oxygen levels are low. Serum lactate levels greater than 2 mmol/L indicate lactic acid production is exceeding lactic acid clearance. Lactic acidosis is the most common cause of metabolic acidosis.</medicine>
		<medicine medName="Larynx" letter="l" audioFile="">Located in the anterior aspect of the neck, the larynx is located superior to the trachea and is where the vocal cords are located. The primary function of the larynx is to protect the trachea from aspiration of fluid or food. Other functions include phonation (production of sound), coughing, and control of ventilation.  </medicine>
		<medicine medName="Lymphatics" letter="l" audioFile="">An extensive network of vessels that travel through almost all body tissues. The lymphatic system is an important part of the immune system and also plays an important role in maintaining fluid balance and absorbing fats and fat-soluble nutrients. Lymph fluid is transported through lymphatics toward the heart. Lymph contains lymphocytes, waste products, cellular debris, bacteria, and proteins.</medicine>
		<medicine medName="Lymphocytes" letter="l" audioFile="">Description here.</medicine>
		<medicine medName="Macrosomia" letter="m" audioFile="media/Macrosomia">Defined as a birth weight greater than or equal to 4,000 grams (4 kilograms).</medicine>
		<medicine medName="Metabolic Conditions" letter="m" audioFile="">Refers to “inborn errors of metabolism,” one of a number of genetic disorders that are usually caused by a block in a metabolic pathway secondary to a defect in an enzyme or transport protein. Primary effects include either toxic accumulation of substrates that cannot be metabolized or broken down, or inability to make an essential product because of a missing intermediary.  </medicine>
		<medicine medName="Metamyelocyte" letter="m" audioFile="">Description here.</medicine>
		<medicine medName="Methylxanthines" letter="m" audioFile="">A class of medications used for bronchodilation, e.g., aminophylline and theophylline. Caffeine is also a methylxanthine and is used to treat apnea of prematurity. Signs of methylxanthine toxicity include vomiting, sinus tachycardia, tachyarrhythmias, and central nervous system excitation.</medicine>
		<medicine medName="Monocytes" letter="m" audioFile="">Description here.</medicine>
		<medicine medName="Myeloblast" letter="m" audioFile="">Description here.</medicine>
		<medicine medName="Myelocyte" letter="m" audioFile="">Description here.</medicine>
		<medicine medName="Necrotizing Enterocolitis (NEC)" letter="n" audioFile="">An acute inflammatory medical condition that most commonly affects preterm infants, although sick term infants may also develop NEC. In addition to prematurity, other risk factors for development of NEC include congenital heart disease, gastroschisis, and/or hypoxic ischemic events. The severest forms of NEC involve intestinal necrosis and perforation.</medicine>
		<medicine medName="Neuroglycopenia" letter="n" audioFile="media/neuroglycopenia">Inadequate glucose supply for normal brain metabolism and function.</medicine>
		<medicine medName="Neurologic" letter="n" audioFile="">Refers to the central nervous system, which includes the brain, spinal cord, and nerves. Neurologic disorders in neonates can manifest as a depressed level of consciousness, hypotonia, seizures, abnormal reflexes, respiratory compromise, cardiovascular instability, and difficulties with eating and swallowing. </medicine>
		<medicine medName="Neuromuscular Disease" letter="n" audioFile=""><![CDATA[Disease affecting the muscles, neuromuscular junction, nerves, or anterior horn motor neurons. Affected neonates often present with hypotonia, with or without contractures. They often have difficulty swallowing, as well as <br>respiratory insufficiency.]]> </medicine>
		<medicine medName="Neutrophil" letter="n" audioFile="">Description here.</medicine>
		<medicine medName="Norepinephrine" letter="n" audioFile="media/norepinephrine"><![CDATA[A catecholamine that functions in the brain and body as a hormone and neurotransmitter. Non-shivering thermogenesis (heat production) is regulated by release of norepinephrine from sympathetic nerves that innervate brown <br>adipose tissue.]]></medicine>
		<medicine medName="Nuchal Cord" letter="n" audioFile="">Occurs when the umbilical cord wraps around the fetal neck completely or for 360 degrees. Nuchal cords may be single or multiple and may be loose or tight. A tight nuchal cord interrupts blood flow (oxygen and nutrients) to the fetus and is associated with adverse outcomes including fetal asphyxia and fetal death.</medicine>
		<medicine medName="Omphalocele" letter="o" audioFile=""><![CDATA[A midline abdominal wall defect that allows herniation of intestine and possibly the liver and other organs outside of the abdominal cavity. There is a covering membrane consisting of peritoneum (inside layer), amnion (outside layer), and Wharton jelly between the two layers. At times, the membrane is ruptured, which may cause confusion with a gastroschisis defect. The umbilical cord is inserted into the membrane rather than the abdominal wall. In approximately 70% of cases, associated anomalies are common and include congenital heart disease. Infants with trisomy 13, 18, and other syndromes, including Beckwith-Wiedemann syndrome, may have an omphalocele. The incidence of omphalocele is between 1.5 and 3 per 10,000 births. Omphalocele is known as exomphalos in <br>the United Kingdom.]]></medicine>
		<medicine medName="Parvovirus  B19" letter="p" audioFile="">(Parvovirus B19) Refers to a “small” virus that is highly contagious. In-utero exposure to parvovirus places the fetus in jeopardy. In particular, the fetus may become severely anemic, which leads to hydrops fetalis (congestive heart failure, edema, ascites, pleural effusions). Myocarditis, thrombocytopenia, and hepatic injury, are additional consequences of fetal exposure to parvovirus.</medicine>
		<medicine medName="Patent Ductus Arteriosus (PDA)" letter="p" audioFile="media/patent_ductus_arteriosus_(PDA)">Refers to the intentional or unintentional failure of the ductus arteriosus to close. Intentional reasons for maintaining ductal patency via medication administration (prostaglandin E1 or E2) include treatment of severe forms of congenital heart disease that are ductal-dependent for systemic or pulmonary blood flow. </medicine>
		<medicine medName="Pathogen" letter="p" audioFile="">Any agent, including bacteria, viruses, fungi, or other microorganisms that can produce or cause a disease.</medicine>
		<medicine medName="Perinatal" letter="p" audioFile="media/perinatal">Refers to the period immediately before and after birth. The International Statistical Classification of Diseases (ICD-10) diagnosis code defines “perinatal” as starting at 22 completed weeks and lasting through 7 days after birth. In the U.S. there are varying definitions of “perinatal mortality.” Definition 1 is defined as infant deaths at  &lt; 7 days of age and fetal deaths at 28 or more weeks gestation. Definition 2 includes infant deaths at &lt; 28 days of age and fetal deaths at 20 or more weeks gestation.</medicine>
		<medicine medName="Peripartum Period" letter="p" audioFile="media/perinatal">Refers to the time period shortly before, during, and immediately after delivery.</medicine>
		<medicine medName="Petechiae" letter="p" audioFile="media/Petechiae">Capillaries (small blood vessels) that burst under the skin and form reddish or purplish spots on the skin that appear similar to a rash. Petechiae may be a sign of an underlying hemorrhagic disorder, including infection. Petechiae are commonly present following a breech or precipitous delivery, or if the infant had a tight nuchal cord (face/neck area).</medicine>
		<medicine medName="Placental Abruption" letter="p" audioFile="media/placental_abruption">Premature separation of the placenta from the uterine wall during pregnancy or labor. Separation can be partial or complete. Risk factors include prolonged rupture of membranes, premature rupture of membranes, prior abruption, uterine infection, chronic or pregnancy-induced hypertension, polyhydramnios, cigarette smoking, severe fetal growth restriction, advanced maternal age, abdominal trauma, male gender, and maternal substance use and misuse. Placental abruption affects 1 in 100 pregnancies. </medicine>
		<medicine medName="Placenta Previa" letter="p" audioFile="media/placenta_previa">A placenta that is implanted in the lower part of the uterus near the cervix (marginal) or in varying degrees (partial or total) over the cervix. Risk factors include prior uterine surgery including cesarean section, increased parity, multiple gestation, advanced maternal age, cigarette smoking, and cocaine use. Placenta previa affects 1 in 200 pregnancies. </medicine>
		<medicine medName="Polycythemia" letter="p" audioFile="media/polycythemia"><![CDATA[A condition marked by an abnormal increase in the number of circulating red blood cells. Neonates with polycythemia often have no symptoms. When symptoms are present, they are usually secondary to hyperviscosity and poor tissue perfusion or to other concurrent metabolic derangements such as hypoglycemia<br> and hypocalcemia.]]></medicine>
		<medicine medName="Polyhydramnios" letter="p" audioFile="media/polyhydramnios"><![CDATA[Refers to excessive amounts of amniotic fluid in the amniotic sac. Causes include birth defects or neurologic conditions that affect fetal swallowing, bowel obstruction, renal disorders that increase urine production, maternal diabetes, and intrauterine infection. Presence of polyhydramnios increases the risk for cord prolapse, placental abruption, premature birth, and perinatal death. Polyhydramnios affects <br>1 in 100 pregnancies. ]]></medicine>
		<medicine medName="Pregnancy-Induced Hypertension" letter="p" audioFile="">Description here. </medicine>
		<medicine medName="Preload" letter="p" audioFile="media/Preload">The amount of blood in the heart just prior to the beginning of contraction. The heart squeezes most effectively when the ventricle is filled with just enough blood before each beat to allow the heart muscle to stretch some before contraction, or systole, begins. </medicine>
		<medicine medName="Prenatal" letter="p" audioFile="">Refers to the period before birth. The goal of prenatal care is to promote a healthy pregnancy and birth. Prenatal care can begin with a preconception obstetric evaluation, especially if the future mother has any chronic illnesses, such as diabetes or autoimmune disease, or any prior adverse pregnancy outcomes.</medicine>
		<medicine medName="Promyelocyte" letter="p" audioFile="">Description here.</medicine>
		<medicine medName="Purulent" letter="p" audioFile="">Refers to the presence of pus or drainage of pus. Pus is a thick yellow or green discharge that is composed of dead white blood cells, bacteria, tissue debris, and serum. Pus is produced by infected tissue.</medicine>
		<medicine medName="Recurrent Laryngeal Nerve (RLN)" letter="r" audioFile="media/recurrent_laryngeal_nerve">A branch of the vagus nerve (cranial nerve X) that supplies the cardiac, tracheal, and esophageal branches and terminates as the inferior laryngeal nerve.</medicine>
		<medicine medName="Renal Vein Thrombosis (RVT)" letter="r" audioFile="media/renal_vein_thrombosis_rvt"><![CDATA[A thrombus formation in one or both main renal veins. RVT may also spread to the inferior vena cava. In newborns, causes include maternal diabetes, asphyxia, sepsis, dehydration, shock, and congenital hypercoagulable states. Sudden onset of gross hematuria should prompt investigation for RVT. Bilateral RVT leads to acute <br>kidney failure.]]></medicine>
		<medicine medName="Replogle Tube" letter="r" audioFile="">A double-lumen tube utilized to suction esophageal pouch secretions in babies with esophageal atresia. One lumen of the tube allows for low continuous suction (set suction at 30 to 40 mmHg). The other lumen is for venting to atmospheric air to prevent the tube from adhering to adjacent tissue. The Replogle tube needs frequent attention to keep it clear of obstructing secretions.</medicine>
		<medicine medName="Respiratory Distress Syndrome (RDS)" letter="r" audioFile="media/respiratory_distress_syndrome_rds">A respiratory illness that primarily affects preterm infants and is characterized by deficiency of pulmonary surfactant. Secreted by type II pneumocytes, pulmonary surfactant is a mixture of phospholipids and lipoproteins which help diminish surface tension in the alveoli. Prior to 34 to 36 weeks gestation, inadequate amounts of surfactant are produced, leaving the alveoli prone to collapse. Treatment of RDS involves surfactant administration as well as respiratory support to maintain and support sustained alveolar inflation.</medicine>
		<medicine medName="Rubella" letter="r" audioFile="media/Rubella">A virus commonly known as “German measles.” Rubella is contagious and can be dangerous to the fetus if the mother contracts the virus in the month before conception or in early pregnancy.</medicine>
		<medicine medName="Shoulder Dystocia" letter="s" audioFile="media/shoulder_dystocia"><![CDATA[An acute emergency that occurs after the delivery of the head, when one or both shoulders get caught or stuck above the mother’s pubic bone. Risk factors include maternal obesity, fetal macrosomia, maternal diabetes, and prior history of <br>shoulder dystocia.]]></medicine>
		<medicine medName="Spinal Defects" letter="s" audioFile="media/spinal_defects">Also called neural tube defects (NTD), these abnormalities can occur in the spinal cord, spine, or brain. Spina bifida is the most common type of NTD, and severity can range from mild to severe. Myelomeningocele is the severest form and involves presence of an opening in the skin with protrusion of a sac that contains spinal cord and nerves. Meningocele also presents with protrusion of a sac, but the spinal cord is not contained in the sac. </medicine>
		<medicine medName="Stroke Volume" letter="s" audioFile=""><![CDATA[The amount of blood that is ejected with each heartbeat or contraction of <br>the left ventricle.]]></medicine>
		<medicine medName="Subgaleal Space" letter="s" audioFile="">Refers to the space between the layer of the scalp called the galea aponeurotica and the periosteum of the skull bones (area lining the bone). The subgaleal space extends from above the frontal bone (orbital ridges) to the occipital bone (nape of the neck) and laterally over the temporal bones (from one ear to the other ear). The subgaleal space can accommodate the infant’s entire blood volume. In a term infant, this volume is approximately 80 mL/kg of body weight. Hemorrhage into the subgaleal space is called subgaleal hemorrhage and can produce profound hypovolemic shock.</medicine>		 
		<medicine medName="Surfactant" letter="s" audioFile="media/surfactant"><![CDATA[Pulmonary surfactant is a mixture of lipids and proteins that are formed by type II alveolar cells. Once formed, surfactant is secreted into the alveolar space. The function of surfactant is to reduce the surface tension at the air/liquid interface in the lung, which helps to increase pulmonary compliance and to prevent <br>collapse of alveoli.]]></medicine>
		<medicine medName="Therapeutic Hypothermia (TH)" letter="t" audioFile="media/therapeutic_hypothermia">Also called neuroprotective hypothermia, therapeutic neuroprotective hypothermia, and brain cooling. TH is considered standard of care in the treatment of specific infants with hypoxic-ischemic encephalopathy (HIE). Following the initial ischemic insult to the brain, a series of events lead to death of neurons. TH reduces mortality secondary to HIE and in survivors, decreases the chance that the infant will have major disability. </medicine>
		<medicine medName="Thrombocytopenia" letter="t" audioFile="">Refers to a low platelet count. Thrombocytopenia may result from either decreased platelet production or increased platelet utilization (or destruction) as a result of various pathological conditions.</medicine>
		<medicine medName="Trachea" letter="t" audioFile="">Also known as the "windpipe," the trachea is a cartilaginous tube that connects the upper airway (pharynx and larynx) to the lungs. The trachea begins just under the larynx and extends until it branches into the two primary bronchi that lead to the right and left lungs.</medicine>
		<medicine medName="Tracheostomy" letter="t" audioFile="">A surgical procedure in the cervical trachea that allows insertion of a tube for the purpose of supporting ventilation. </medicine>
		<medicine medName="Twin-to-Twin Transfusion Syndrome (TTS)" letter="t" audioFile="">A serious disorder that occurs in monochorionic (identical) twins who share a placenta and in higher-order multiples who also share a placenta. The shared placenta contains abnormal blood vessels, which connect the umbilical cords and circulations of the twins. The chronic form of TTS results in one twin becoming progressively anemic and growth restricted (donor) and the recipient twin becoming hydropic from congestive heart failure and hypervolemia. The donor twin commonly has too little amniotic fluid (oligohydramnios) and the recipient twin has too much amniotic fluid (polyhydramnios).</medicine>
		<medicine medName="Varicella" letter="v" audioFile="">Description here.</medicine>
		<medicine medName="Vasa Previa" letter="v" audioFile="">Describes fetal umbilical cord blood vessels that run across or very close to the internal opening of the cervix and below the level of the fetal presenting part. These vessels are inside the membranes, unprotected by the umbilical cord or the placenta. As such, they are at risk of rupturing when the membranes break.</medicine>
		<medicine medName="Velamentous Cord Insertion (VCI)" letter="v" audioFile="">Refers to attachment of the umbilical cord into the chorioamnionic membranes, rather than the placenta. The exposed umbilical vessels are unprotected by Wharton’s jelly, which makes them prone to kinking, compression, and rupture.</medicine>
		<medicine medName="Ventricular Septal Defect (VSD)" letter="v" audioFile="">A defect or hole in the wall that divides the left and right ventricles of the heart.</medicine>
		<medicine medName="Virus" letter="v" audioFile=""><![CDATA[ A small microorganism that can only replicate (reproduce) inside the cells of another organism. Viruses invade cells to be able to multiply and produce other viruses <br> like themselves.]]></medicine>
		<medicine medName="Zika Virus" letter="z" audioFile="">Description here.</medicine>
      </chapter>
   </glossary>
</displaySet>
