<Contents id="T04_P7">

  <question id="image0">

	<title><![CDATA[Aspiration]]></title>

    <instruction><![CDATA[Select the correct answer and click <b>Submit</b>.]]></instruction>

    <Options>

       <Option><![CDATA[Sick infants frequently have respiratory distress, which can interfere with their suck, swallow, and breathing coordination.]]></Option>

      <Option><![CDATA[They are easily fatigued and often uninterested in feedings.]]></Option>

      <Option><![CDATA[They often have weak, inadequate feeding effort.]]></Option>

	  <Option><![CDATA[They are at increased risk for aspiration of stomach contents into the lungs.]]></Option>

    </Options>

  </question>

  <question id="image1">

	<title><![CDATA[Intestinal Ileus]]></title>

    <instruction><![CDATA[Select the correct answer and click <b>Submit</b>.]]></instruction>

    <Options>

       <Option><![CDATA[Intestinal ileus is when peristalsis or motility slows significantly or stops altogether.]]></Option>

       <Option><![CDATA[An ileus leads to abdominal distension and delayed gastric emptying.]]></Option>

       <Option><![CDATA[This increases the risk for aspiration of stomach contents into the lungs.]]></Option>

    </Options>

  </question>

  <question id="image2">

  <title><![CDATA[Hypoxemia and Impaired Blood Flow to the Bowel]]></title>

  <instruction><![CDATA[Select the correct answer and click <b>Submit</b>.]]></instruction>

  <Options>

	  <Option><![CDATA[Severe hypoxemia may lead to intestinal injury.]]></Option>

      <Option><![CDATA[If the fetus or newborn is hypotensive prior to, during, or after birth, the body diverts blood away from non-vital organs.]]></Option>

      <Option><![CDATA[Inadequate intestinal blood flow makes it more susceptible to <span  style="color:#e4bb4d;" href="javascript:void(0)" class="glossarytag" glossaryTitle= "Ischemia/Ischemic" textDesc="Restriction in blood supply and therefore in oxygen delivery to the tissues. Secondary effects include poor nutrient delivery to the tissues and inadequate removal of metabolic wastes. Ischemia results in tissue damage and may progress to tissue necrosis.">ischemic</span> injury.]]></Option>

	  <Option><![CDATA[Allow the bowel enough time to recover from any injury that may have occurred.]]></Option>

	  <Option><![CDATA[Bowel rest involves withholding feedings, starting an IV, and providing glucose-containing solutions to help maintain normal blood sugar.]]></Option>

  </Options>

</question>

</Contents>

